## MARK WATSON

St Ives, NSW Australia 2075

0448 488 884 | Email: mark@watsonised.me

Portfolio: https://get.watsonised.me | GitHub: https://github.com/Mark33Mark

**Linkedin:** https://www.linkedin.com/in/mark-watsonised/

# Summary

Full stack web developer with a property development and capital transactions background. With a deep understanding of electronics and programming using different languages and environments to deliver great user experiences. Past and current projects demonstrate creativity and an outstanding technical capability to develop meaningful applications for everyday use.

Completed a certificate in full stack development at the University of Sydney to further advance his skills in developing responsive and accessible applications.

Highly capable developing in agile teams using git. Effectively delivers from well articulated briefs or high level conceptual requests.

#### Technical Skills

Languages: JavaScript, CSS, HTML, C, Python, PHP, SQL

Applications: GitHub, mySQL, Mongoose, API, S3, DynamoDB, EC2

Tools: AWS, Netlify, Express, React, Redux, Node, Handlebars, mongoDB

## **Projects**

Flickering: An installable, progressive web application (PWA) developed using a MERN stack. The app was created for mood / emotion tracking. Uploaded and hosted on Heroku platform.

**GitHub:** https://github.com/Mark33Mark/flickering

Quot3d: mySQL database of quotes that randomly selects a quote for the user. Express and Nodejs used for the server side. Uploaded and hosted on Heroku platform.

**Live app:** https://quot3d.netlify.app

GitHub: https://github.com/Mark33Mark/quoted

Weather Dashboard: API application that makes server calls to the OpenWeather API for weather in locations around the world as configured by the user. Includes a 7 day forecast and makes use of a graphical interface for improved user experience.

Live app: https://sun.watsonised.me

GitHub: https://github.com/Mark33Mark/weather-dashboard

Lettuce eat: API application that accesses the Spoonacular API for recipes. Concept was around the user typing in the key ingredient and the application generates recipe ideas. Extensive user configuration provided.

Live app: https://eat.watsonised.me

**GitHub:** https://github.com/Mark33Mark/recipe-generator

## Experience

#### CSR Limited, Sydney NSW — Property and Development Manager

Nov 2023 – present

Managing a portfolio of 120 leases and 50 freehold properties. Responsible for driving the property strategy across the various CSR business units. Developed an application from ground up to assist with the management of the portfolio.

**Accomplishments:** developed property management application, full stack application with secure login using JWT tokens and server-client handshakes.

Website: https://csr-property.netlify.app \_\_\_\_

#### **Learnosity Pty Ltd, Sydney NSW** — Software Developer

Feb 2022 - Nov 2023

Agile team work, developing new features and resolving bugs in an EdTech API business that averages about 3 million hits per day to education software.

**Accomplishments:** developed a drag and drop component as a react hook.

Make No Symposium

#### Watsonised Pty Ltd, Sydney NSW — Developer / Consultant

July 2019 – Feb 2022

My company I created to provide development consultancy services.

**Accomplishments:** Developer and site administrator for Prospero's online presence.

Website: https://prosperocommerce.com

## **Woolworths Group, Sydney NSW** — Regional Development Manager

January 2012 – June 2019

Developed and implemented investment strategies for the expansion of the property business in NSW.

**Accomplishments:** Sought and received board approval to sell approximately 130 properties with a combined value of over \$200M and profit of \$20M over a 2-year period. Completed sale of the properties inside the 2-year period. Acquired and developed approximately 20 properties for neighbourhood centres anchored by Woolworths.

#### Education

### **Coding Bootcamp Certificate – Full Stack Developer** — *University of Sydney*

August 2021 – February 2022, Sydney NSW Australia

Course focused on technical programming skills in: HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, JavaScript ES6+, Node, SQL, Heroku, Mongoose, Express and React.

## **Bachelor of Building Construction Management** — *University of NSW*

Attained 1st class honours for a 5 year degree including completion of a thesis. Selected by the computer science lecturer to tutor the computer science stream of the course. Received the Multiplex monetary prize for highest marks during the course in construction subjects.